<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Nikhil's Thoughts]]></title>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://yoursite.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-11T08:37:59-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://yoursite.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nikhil Thomas]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Reflecting on my Ruby education]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/11/reflecting-on-my-ruby-education/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-11T07:39:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/11/reflecting-on-my-ruby-education</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m incredibly fortunate to be attending the <a href="http://www.flatironschool.com">Flatiron School</a> here in NYC from October through December taking lessons on Ruby, Rails, Javascsript and other web technologies. It&#8217;s been really exciting to try and educate myself about what goes on under the hood on all my favorite web applications. However, not all learning styles work equally well for me.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Typically in college, I&#8217;ve been able to just do practice questions to solidify my understanding. That hasn&#8217;t worked as well when it came to programming languages, particularly in picking up Ruby as a beginner. Luckily there&#8217;s a variety of resources available online and here are some of the tools I&#8217;ve used.</p>

<p>1) <strong>Videos to start</strong> - The best way I&#8217;ve been able to start a new topic is by watching a video on the topic. Some of my favorite resources include <a href="http://www.codeschool.com">Code School</a> and <a href="http://www.treehouse.com">Treehouse</a>. The videos are short and brief, but provide sample questions at the end so you can really drill down and make sure you understand a topic. I will say that I found Code School&#8217;s format to be less like a formal lecture and a little more engaging.</p>

<p>2) <strong>Screencasts are awesome</strong> - Michael Hartl has what is probably the definitive <a href="http://www.ruby.railstutorial.org">Ruby on Rails tutorial</a> available. He makes his book available for free and the screencasts are only $125. Seriously, invest in these and refer to them whenever you get stuck. He&#8217;s a great speaker who can take a complex topic and concisely break it down into baby steps. Plus you can take the PDF on the go like I do and skim topics to review whenever you need to. It&#8217;s awesome.</p>

<p>3) <strong>Looking at practice code</strong> - Videos, screencasts and books are great but at the end of the day, you&#8217;re not a programmer if you don&#8217;t program. For that, I&#8217;ve been scouring the internet for Rails programmers in fields I&#8217;m interested in and trying to find their Github accounts. It&#8217;s been really helpful to see how people tackle problems, what clean code looks like, and what you&#8217;re capable of doing. A good place to start looking would be open source projects like Octopress (which I use for this blog). PS - if you know of any growth hackers who show off code, <a href="mailto:nikhil@flatironschool.com?Subject=Growth%20Hacker%20Code">email me!</a></p>

<p>How did you learn to code? Can you think of any other resources for a beginner? Finding Ruby was like falling in love, and Carl Sagan once said that when you&#8217;re in love, you want to share it with the world. Let&#8217;s share tips and tricks!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[SQL joins are HARD]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/10/sql-joins-are-hard/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-10T16:18:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/10/sql-joins-are-hard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here at the Flatiron School, we&#8217;re building out our own internal feedback tool, which is wonderfully named Feedbackadoro (if you disapprove, please yell at <a href="http://www.twitter.com/aviflombaum">Avi</a>). We started out by building the SQL tables and some practice queries, and I&#8217;m pretty sure I need a lot more work to understand JOINs&#8230;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Imagine for a moment that you have three tables - one for users of the tool, one for submitted issues, and one for submitted solutions.</p>

<p>Got it?</p>

<p>Great. Now, I had to establish a personal understanding of what the tool would be used for and get into the mindset of the consumer. I felt that, if I were using the tool, I would want to be able to search for questions that were marked as CLOSED and had submitted answers from an instructor of the class. I then wanted to SELECT the name of the user, the content of the issue and the content of the solution</p>

<p>Having to INNER JOIN all three of the tables was tough, I wasn&#8217;t sure if order mattered at first - would I need to join the user table before the solution? It turned out that the mistake I had the entire time wasn&#8217;t a mistake at all! I wrote a query that outputted a blank entry in bash, but I thought it was breaking. Turns out my query was asking for all issues submitted by instructors. My tables didn&#8217;t have that issue at all, why would instructors ask students for help?</p>

<p>Turns out the hardest part of joins isn&#8217;t implementing them, but understanding the question you&#8217;re trying to solve.</p>

<p>Have you had trouble with joins? What kept you up at night?</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I'm editing my config]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/im-editing-my-config/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T17:18:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/im-editing-my-config</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m going to be incredibly embarrassed of all this if I forget it and it leaks to the public.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Practice makes not-quite-perfect-but-not-as-horrible]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/practice-makes-not-quite-perfect-but-not-as-horrible/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T16:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/practice-makes-not-quite-perfect-but-not-as-horrible</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s day two of class and I&#8217;m already starting to slowly understand (grok?) some of the very core technologies. I have to admit, Git was slightly intimidating when I started but I&#8217;m learning the workflow properly. I&#8217;ve picked up a few rookie tips.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I think if there are three things I would recommend to anyone who wants to start learning how to code, they would be :</p>

<ol>
    <li><strong>Work with people</strong> - Having people to bounce thoughts and ideas off is easily the best part of this class. Trying to learn on my own was hard, but not impossible. Being around smart and motivated people prevented me from falling behind or getting lazy.</li>
    <li> <strong>Practice a LOT</strong> - This is rather obvious, but the only way to learn how to code is to code. Reading books, watching videos, that&#8217;s all helpful but not the most important thing you can do. It&#8217;s imperative to write crappy code, screw up and learn how to fix it.</li>
    <li> <strong>Customize your environment</strong> - I HATE the standard Mac OS X terminal. All that black-against-white just hurts my eyes. Get it away. Once I tuned the colors and shortcuts to my liking, everything started to fly.</li> 
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Title Here]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/title-here/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T15:43:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/title-here</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Here is where you put your text.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[A Great Supervillain Quote]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/a-great-supervillain-quote/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T15:01:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/a-great-supervillain-quote</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote><p>Do you feel in charge?</p><footer><strong>Bane</strong> <cite><a href='http://www.amazon.com/Knight-Rises-Blu-ray-UltraViolet-Digital/dp/B004LWZWGK/ref=sr_tr_sr_1?ie=UTF8&qid=1349290864&sr=8-1&keywords=the+dark+knight+rises'>The Dark Knight Rises</a></cite></footer></blockquote>


<p>Sent chills down my spine.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Testing out HTML Code]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/testing-out-html-code/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T14:53:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/testing-out-html-code</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I&#8217;m going to test out the <strong>bold</strong>, <em>italics</em> and <a href="http://www.google.com">Google link</a> too.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Superhero Game I've Played]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/the-catchiest-wiz-khalifa-song-ive-heard/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T14:44:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/the-catchiest-wiz-khalifa-song-ive-heard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Video after the jump.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><video width='640' height='320' preload='none' controls poster=' http://s3.imathis.com/video/zero-to-fancy-buttons.png'><source src='http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rrfo8XaVTDI' type='video/mp4; codecs="avc1.42E01E, mp4a.40.2"'/></video></p>

<p>Couldn&#8217;t find a good poster picture so there you go.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Nikhil's Hello World]]></title>
    <link href="http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/nikhils-hello-world/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-03T14:27:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://yoursite.com/blog/2012/10/03/nikhils-hello-world</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>&#8220;Let&#8217;s add some test content to this page. Hopefully this will show up on the blog.&#8221;</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>&#8220;This should appear after the fold and the continue button.&#8221;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
